The video you're about to watch has no redstone dust, no redstone torches,
no redstone blocks, no redstone repeaters, and no redstone comparators,
because in this video we're going to be using the brand new redstone component
introduced in this week's snapshot, the wind charge.
Now you may be asking yourself, Crafty, how the hell is the wind charge a redstone component?
Most of you probably know it for its movement-based properties.
For example, I can scale up this mountain just using a few breeze balls,
and there you go, I can get to the top. And since they're a projectile, you can also fire them
from dispensers. So you can basically make a bunch of different player cannons like this. So I've kind of made like this little obstacle
course. So we're going to try and run through it without failing. Surely. So first, we hop on this
platform. As you can see, you also take no fall damage when you use the wind charge.
So now we're going to try, aim for that platform. There we go. Come on, get it, land on it.
And then we get our button and our other wind charge, even though I already have one.
You can also clutch with these if you time it right, so I hope I do this first try because I'm not very good at it.
And...
Which means, of course, we're're gonna get it second try surely there you go we
can clutch it with the wind charges so I'm gonna try and get in there come on there we
go we place our buttonore that one piece of redstone dust.
And finally we launch ourselves to the final platform.
All the way up to the gold over here.
So this is just a small taste of what you can do movement base,
so you can probably make way more elaborate courses using these wind charges.
But another thing you may not know about them
is that they can actually interact with all of these different blocks right here.
So if I throw a wind charge at all of these, as you can see, the fence gate opens, the lever gets flicked,
trapdoor can also open.
Button gets pushed.
Also doors can open.
Bells can get rung.
And also candles can actually get extinguished.
So if I light this again, you can see that they're lit, and then you can turn them off like this.
And the activation range for this is like roughly like two blocks away in like a circle like
this. It's a little bit random because it's a projectile and has a little bit of random motion.
But yeah, two block radius is roughly the activation range.
So one of the first things I tried was making a screen that you can also draw on.
So as you can see, all you have to do is just kind of fire the balls roughly where you want to paint. And look, you can make a smiley face just like that. And you can also erase it. If you kind of do it, again, it's not the most consistent.
And that is the problem with a lot of these very small drawable screens. They can't really be
reset too easily. Of course, until now.
Because if you happen to use trap doors,
instead of copper bulbs with buttons on top of them,
you can both draw on the trap doors like this.
So again, let's make a really derpy looking smiley face that looks like it's on a snowman.
But you can also reset the screen right over there, as you can see all the trap doors get pulsed and the screen gets
white. And the redstone back here is so simple. It's literally just a wall with some trap
doors with just a bunch of observer spam that activates all the track doors and it's just powered by this other
trapdoor which you can also shoot one of these wind charges at. I'm not going to lie, I don't
know how much the name wind charge is going to stick. I think Breeze Ball is a way better name for it.
I mean, we already have the Blaze Rod, so it kind of makes sense to have the Breeze balls.
Wait a minute. Moving away from questionable jokes, you can also make piston doors using these.
So as you can see, if you throw the wind charge, I'm going to be calling the breeze balls
for the rest of this video.
As you can see, you can activate two levers at the same time.
Now, that is, if you put it in the middle.
If you do it even slightly off to one side,
it's not gonna be the most consistent.
You have to make sure you hit it dead on
in the center for it to work consistently. Which is why you can
automate the process even more by dispensing the breeze balls from dispensers. So here we
have a very basic 3x3 door with a hole in the middle.
That gets activated by this kind of like increasing cone shape of dispensers.
So as you can see in the very front layer, we have all of our levers that activate all of these
pistons,
and then they get powered by these dispensers with these breeze balls,
and then you kind of make these as close together as you can,
so all of these buttons are nice and close,
so then you can have another pair of dispensers activate these buttons are nice and close, so then you can have another pair of dispensers activate
these buttons. So then you just kind of get like a chain reaction, and you get a very basic
piston door. But obviously only using single piston extenders is pretty limiting, so the next thing
I wanted to do was a double piston extender.
So here is one version over here.
Look at it.
It's beautiful.
Basically, this button powers these sets of back pistons, and then the breeze ball gets dispensed, and then it hits this lever like this, and then it stays on, and then on retraction, it also hits this button, which will activate the pistons and do the final
retraction.
Just like that.
So combining normal pistons with a double piston extender, the first Breeze Ball
base door I made was the 4x4 Vault Door.
Now Breeze Ball Door is kinda hard to say.
There's a lot of consonant sounds and I don't really like it.
So what's the best way to describe a door in which the jobs of activating all the levers is done by blowing them.
The blowjob door.
So if we look at the wiring for a bit, you can see over here we have the double piston extender from before,
just slightly oriented a little differently, but we still have the button here, the lever,
and the last button for the retraction. And then the rest is kind of just wiring that goes all around
the door to activate these outer pistons. Okay, so double piston extenders may be able to take
us to vault doors like this with two layers, but what if you still want to make a normal 3x3? Well, it'd probably be
beneficial to have some one-tick generators. That's right, we have a one-tick generator over here.
It is very small, and it just
uses two dispensers full of
breeze balls. One is right up
against this block, and the other is kind of
like one block away. So we get
two ball collisions,
but the collisions are just spaced out enough
where it only gives a one-tick pulse.
So this lever kind of gets spammed
on and off very quickly, just like that.
So now that we have double piss extenders and one tick pulses,
the next step is obviously a 3x3 piston door.
This is the 3x3 BJ door.
Look at it. Look how beautiful it is. It is very complicated. I mean, I can try my
best to explain it, but I don't expect any of you to understand. So the first part is the Piston Layout.
This is the Piston Layout for the middle three blocks, and it goes a little something like this.
So first, this double piston extender on the bottom, extends like this, then it pushes there, and then it kind of stays here.
So then we have this bottom block of the 3x3.
Then the top part goes off and we get a one tick pulse here, we kind of get like a button
pulse on this piston, and then a second one tick pulse here, we kind of get like a button pulse on this piston, and then a second one tick
pulse on this piston again. And there you go, we have the closing. God damn it, I can't avoid
references to these. And then on the opening, we just do the double piston extension again, except this time
it'll actually push the blocks up here, this piston retracts that block, this piston
retracts this, and finally the double piston extender retracts back into the ground.
So we can see that in the double when we push the button.
As you can see it pushed all the way up, and then it retracted only once, leaving this bottom block.
And then on the opening, you can see that it's going to push all the blocks into the ceiling.
And then again, to get the sticky piston to spit out its block,
we have two one-tick generators because this thing has to fire twice.
There is one more interesting property about these kinds of doors though.
So if we just look at the closing one more time,
as you can see, this piston actually stays extended,
but there are no inputs on it.
The reason is because we have this button over here
and this button on top activating the one tick generator.
So this activates it, and then this keeps the powered on
because of quasi connectivity.
Which means when this double piston extender pushes the block in front of this piston,
it's going to be able to instantly retract without us even putting an input.
So that means on the opening, we actually only need one one tick pulse instead of two one
tick pulses. So we have this lever over here, which basically means that when it's on, which is
when it's closed, it's going to power the top section. But when it's on, which is when it's closed,
it's going to power the top section.
But when it opens, this lever will turn off,
meaning the dispenser won't actually fire in the opening.
So we can see that happening right here.
As you can see, the lever turned off, and this part of the door never got powered. If you want to see the lever logic more clearly, we have like a setup over here.
The middle lamp will activate every time I push this button, and the side lamps will
alternate.
So right now the right lamp just went on, and now the left lamp will go on, and then again, the right lamp will go on.
So that is how you can have like an on and off edge pulse kind of thing on a button input like this.
So now what if we combine to all of the knowledge of our double piston extenders,
our one-tick pulses, and our newfound lever logic?
Well, we get the world's first 4x4 BJ door.
And as you can see, this thing looks insane.
It's like shattering into like lots of tiny pieces as it gets further.
And yes, it does have to be this big.
And another thing, it's pretty unreliable, so hopefully it works the first time I push it.
So there we go. The door will close.
Nicely like that and is actually in sync, which is pretty rare.
And let's see if it opens.
There we go.
And now the double piss and extenders are gonna go off.
And there you go.
The 4x4 has opened.
So I also went ahead and took this angle from the door, just so you can see all the pistons
and all the breeze balls hitting all the levers and buttons.
Am I going to explain how this works? Probably not, since it is really complicated,
but it does use that lever logic we just talked about to control the double piston
extender on the opening and only power the back pistons on the closing.
You guys also have no idea how many takes it took me to open this door.
Because the thing is, this is hella unreliable, especially this dispenser over here.
This thing fires a breeze ball.
Sometimes it doesn't hit that platform
and it just flies past.
So yeah, that is the end of Crafty Masterman
making yet another snapshot video
and giving the latest component a really stupid name.
Hopefully, like the other two times, it doesn't get nerved into oblivion.