You wanted to come this time.
Zay-in-pah!
Little Fis!
Big Tis!
You were gone forever!
It was three days.
Where are we going?
Before Mali stole Tifiti's heart.
Our ancestors,
I wanted to connect our island to all the people of the entire ocean.
It's my job as a wavefinder to finish what they started.
Wanna show how people?
Just how far we'll go.
This is a call from the ancestors.
Hidden in a terrible storm.
It's an ancient island.
Sitting foot on its sands would break the curse.
Bring our people together again.
I know what I have to do.
Mowie, I could really use your help.
Can I get a Chi-hoo?
You will be destroyed.
And your wayfinder too.
Now I kind of miss the lava monster.
Ow!
What if you don't come back?
I'll be back.
I promise.
Do I hear people?
Those aren't people.
Cockham.
Yeah.
You guys, we got this.
Oh, whoa!
Bring it on, Coke.
Nuts.
Go!
See, I'm in my mind.
Super!
Woo!